<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Syntax Layer</title>
    <link>https://syntax-layer.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Syntax Layer</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://syntax-layer.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Wallet Is Not Neutral</title>
      <link>https://syntax-layer.com/articles/the-wallet-is-not-neutral/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://syntax-layer.com/articles/the-wallet-is-not-neutral/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What Coinbase&amp;rsquo;s Agentic Wallets actually change — and what they don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every significant infrastructure event contains a hidden philosophical claim. When Coinbase launched Agentic Wallets on February 11, they announced it as a developer tool. What they actually shipped was a position on what agents are.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Until now, AI agents could reason, retrieve, and respond. They could draft emails, write code, and summarize documents. But they couldn&amp;rsquo;t pay for anything. They had no economic skin in the game — no way to acquire resources, compensate services, or participate in transactions without a human holding the card. The wallet changes this. Not because money is what matters, but because economic participation is a form of subjectivity. An agent with a wallet isn&amp;rsquo;t just a function. It&amp;rsquo;s an actor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Boring Parts Problem: Why Manufacturing Leaders Can&#39;t Get Excited About What Actually Works</title>
      <link>https://syntax-layer.com/articles/the-boring-parts-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://syntax-layer.com/articles/the-boring-parts-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a behavioral puzzle hiding in plain sight: manufacturing COOs are systematically investing in AI tools that look impressive while under-investing in the capabilities that determine whether those tools actually work. They know this. The data is clear. And yet the pattern persists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t about ignorance or incompetence. It&amp;rsquo;s about psychology—the cognitive and organizational forces that make certain investments irresistible and others invisible, regardless of what the evidence says about effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 15 Millisecond Ceiling: Why Latency Sensitivity Will Shape AI Adoption Patterns</title>
      <link>https://syntax-layer.com/articles/the-15-millisecond-ceiling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://syntax-layer.com/articles/the-15-millisecond-ceiling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The psychological threshold that infrastructure builders know—and product designers keep forgetting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We never decided to abandon slow websites. We just stopped visiting them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2006, Google engineers discovered something that changed how we build technology: for every 100 milliseconds of added latency, they lost 0.6 percent of searches. Amazon found that every 100-millisecond delay cost them 1 percent of sales. The pattern was consistent across studies: human patience for digital delay has a hard ceiling, and it&amp;rsquo;s measured in fractions of a second.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Inference Economy: Why Real-Time AI Access Becomes the New Competitive Moat</title>
      <link>https://syntax-layer.com/articles/the-inference-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://syntax-layer.com/articles/the-inference-economy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where value shifts in AI infrastructure—and what it means for your competitive strategy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most consequential number in AI infrastructure isn&amp;rsquo;t about model size or training compute. It&amp;rsquo;s 35 percent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the compound annual growth rate McKinsey projects for AI inference workloads through 2030—when inference will consume more than 90 gigawatts of data center capacity and represent over half of all AI compute demand. Training workloads, by comparison, will grow at 22 percent CAGR. The infrastructure story is shifting from building bigger models to serving them faster.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
